我记得在肯尼迪文化中心过的八岁生日
I remember my 8th birthday at the KCC
有个超大的蛋糕
with that giant cake
伊维姑妈休假过来了  给了大家一个惊喜
and Aunt Evie showing up on leave, surprising all of us.
我记得妈妈
I remember Mom.
我记得科奇
I remember Codger.
我记得上学  去看电影
I remember school and going to the movies
周五晚上吃披萨  动画片
and Friday-night pizza and cartoons
祖父母  教堂
and Grandma and Grandpa and church,
夏季烧烤  还有你给我买的儿童泳池
those summer barbecues, and the kiddie pool you got me.
要是监狱有就好了
Could've used that at the prison.
你说过我三岁时我们去散步
You told me about the walks we'd take when I was 3,
你拉着我的手  在街区漫步
you holding my hand, around the neighborhood,
去了罗斯的农场
all the way to Ross' farm.
我不知道我还记得那一切  但我真记得
I didn't know that I remembered them, but I do.
因为我能看见阳光  玉米
'Cause I see the sun and the corn
走到篱笆边上看着我眼睛的奶牛
and that cow that walked up to the fence and looked me in the eye.
你跟我说过这一切
And you told me about all that stuff,
但重点不是那些事
but it isn't just that stuff.
而是我的感受
It's how I felt.
牵着你的手  我觉得幸福  特别
Holding your hand, I felt happy and special.
我觉得安全
I felt safe.
我以为成长就是找份工作
I thought growing up was about getting a job
组建家庭  做个成年人
and maybe a family, being an adult,
但成长其实是保证你自己
but growing up is making yourself
和你爱的人的安全
and the people you love safe --
尽可能地安全  因为会有意外发生
as safe as you can, because things happen.
之前就发生过
They happened before.
一切变糟之前你中枪了
You were shot before things went bad.
感觉好像一切变糟就是因为你中枪了
Kind of felt like things went bad because you were shot.
我希望让你觉得安全  爸爸
I want to make you feel safe, Dad.
我希望让你感受到你牵着我时我的感受
I want you to feel just like I felt when you held my hand.
就那样感受五分钟
Just to feel that way for five minutes.
我宁愿付出一切  让你现在也有那种感受
I'd give anything to make you feel that way now.
我曾想杀了尼根
I wanted to kill Negan.
真希望我做到了  也许就结束了
I wish I did. Maybe it would've been done.
我觉得现在还没结束  你又出去了
I don't think it's done now. You went out there again,
但我觉得他们没投降
but I don't think they surrendered.
我觉得他们不会投降
I don't think they will surrender.
救世堂里面有工人  爸爸
There are workers in there, Dad.
他们只是普通人
They're just regular people --
老人  年轻人  家人
old people, young people, families.
你不希望他们死掉  爸爸
You don't want them to die, Dad.
我们差一点就可以重新开始了
We're so close to starting everything over,
我们现在有朋友了
and we have friends now.
这就是耶稣说过的更广阔的世界
It's that bigger world Jesus talked about --
神之国  山顶寨
the Kingdom, the Hilltop --
肯定还有更多地方
there's -- there's got to be more places,
更多人
more people out there,
让一切改变  继续改变的机会
a chance for everything to change and keep changing,
大家给彼此生活的机会
everyone giving everyone the opportunity to have a life --
真正的生活
a real life.
所以如果他们不终结这一切  那你就必须这样做
So if they won't end it, you have to.
你必须给他们一条出路
You have to give them a way out.
你得跟尼根和平共处
You have to find peace with Negan,
想办法找到前进的道路
find a way forward somehow.
我们没必要忘掉发生的事
We don't have to forget what happened,
但你可以确保那些事不再发生
but you can make it so that it won't happen again,
没人必须那样生活
that nobody has to live this way,
每个生命都是有价值的
that every life is worth something.
重新开始吧
Start everything over.
向大家展示无需杀戮也能重获安全
Show everyone that they can be safe again without killing,
能重新有安全感
that it can feel safe again,
一切能回到过去的样子
that it could go back to being birthdays
生日  上学  上班
and school and jobs and
甚至是周五晚上吃披萨
even Friday-night pizza somehow.
爸爸和三岁小孩手拉手散步
And walks with a dad and a 3-year-old holding hands.
让那一切回来吧  爸爸
Make that come back, Dad.
继续跟朱迪思散步吧
And go on those walks with Judith.
她会记得的
She'll remember them.
我爱你
I love you.
卡尔
Carl.
尼根
《行尸走肉》
我回来是为了弥补过错
I came back here to make amends.
你让我看起来像个混蛋
You made me look like an ass.
我的情报不够新
My intel wasn't current.
亚历山大的情况变了
You know, things changed at Alexandria.
魅力
Juice.
魅力和势头能改变局势
Juice and momentum can change the game.
他们有  也改变了
They had it, and they did it.
玛格丽特掌控了山顶寨
Margaret had the Hilltop by the nuts.
我当时不知道
I didn't know it.
是  我们付出了代价
And, yes, we paid a price.
但让我向尼根赎罪吧
But let me make it right with Negan, hmm?
我就是尼根
I'm Negan.
我说的不是集体的"我们都是尼根"那一套
And not in a collective, "We're all Negan" sense.
我是救世军的现任掌权者
I have assumed control of the Saviors.
尼根已经下线了
Negan is no longer on the field of play.
现在你是老大吗
You're the man now?
是的
I am.
我就知道
I knew it.
我就知道你能行
I knew you could do it.
尼根很有个性  我知道
Negan was a big personality, I get it,
但他...
but, uh...
太标新立异了
too unconventional.
心慈手软
Pulled his punches.
没错
Exactly.
而你恰恰是那种大家可以依赖的
Whereas you are the kind of man people can look at
并赞美"这才像是个领袖"的人
and say, "Now there is a leader."
正因如此
Which is why
我才不能让大家看到我对你留情
I can't be seen going easy on you.
做做场面
Optics.
你现在不用担心场面的问题
You don't have to worry about optics now.
-因为你...  -我知道
- 'Cause you -- - ‭Oh, I know.
我有那种魅力
I have that juice.
我有那种势头
I have that momentum.
我想保持下去
I want to keep it.
因此  你得上路
Ergo, you go.
那真是惊人的愚蠢
Well, that is just breathlessly stupid.
没错
Yep.
你觉得这里这群原始人
You think these Troglodytes here
会在管理社区上
are gonna advise you in managing communities,
以及整合资源上给你建议吗
in resource reallocations?
还有政治上
In politics?
没错
That's right, yeah,
残酷无情的政治
the bare-knuckle gnad mash of politics?
已经  结束了  格雷戈里
It is ended, Gregory.
不  我已经取得了这么多成就
No! I've achieved too much!
我受了这么多苦
I-I-I've suffered too much!
我生存了这么久  不是为了这种结局
I've survived too much for it to end like this!
我走在风口浪尖
I've lashed myself to the bow,
经历了大风大浪
seen through the storm,
重生成了一名合格的问题解决者
and I have been reborn as a-a certified shit kicker!
我能做成事
I make things happen!
我总是能做成事
I've always made things happen.
这一切不能以我走进荒野
And it's not gonna end with me wandering off into the wilderness
手里抓着自己的鸟为结局
with my dick in my hand.
在一切分崩离析时我力挽狂澜
I put things together when everything fell apart,
我可以再次做到这点
and I can do it again.
我会再次做到这点的
I will do it again.
你他妈算哪根葱来说我完了
You know, who the hell are you to tell me I'm done?
你以为自己有魅力是吧
Yeah, you think you have the juice?
老子就是魅力化身
Well, I am the juice!
不
No!
首先...
First...
我不是要赶走你
I wasn't gonna send you away.
我是要杀了你
I was gonna kill you.
其次...
Second...
你会煮咖啡吗
do you make coffee?
地表最香
Best in the land.
那就先从煮咖啡开始  然后再说
We'll start with coffee and see where it goes.
他还在外面
He's still out here.
我们走的时候没看见他
Didn't see him when we left.
也许他终于放弃了
Maybe he finally gave up.
不  他不会的
Nope. He won't.
除非是在我们的逼迫之下
Not unless we make him.
我们应该直接杀了他
We should just kill him.
我来
I got it.
早告诉你了
Told ya.
他有吃过东西吗
Has he eaten?
我们做出了选择
We made our choice.
他想死在树林里
He wants to die in the woods,
指望着我们改变想法
hoping we change our minds.
那是他自己的选择
That's his choice.
去找点水喝吧
Find yourself some water.
在我看来这是浪费大蒜
Seems like a waste of good garlic to me.
也是浪费其他食材
And everything else.
我给你们的沙丁鱼芝士通心粉配方
That sardine mac-and-cheese recipe I gave you
是我大学时期的主食
was a staple from my college days
作为一个囊中羞涩的学生
when, ‭as a cash-strapped student,
我得尽可能搭配好经济实惠的
I had to pad out ‭the budget-minded goodness
芝士末和通心粉
of M-and-powdered-C
以及沙丁鱼罐头所含的蛋白质...
with the protein power of canned sardines...
这能比碳水化合物更加长久地
which provided ‭a longer-lasting energy source
为人体提供能量
than pure carbohydrates.
而煎大蒜纯粹是一次巧合的发现
The garlic sauté alleys what originated as a purely "Oops" dish.
唤起了我的回忆
Takes me back.
开始装盘吧  今后只吃这道菜
Start plating it up. This is all that's on the menu
直到订单完成
for the rest of the time till this order's complete.
我想提醒大家  我们的性命没有保障
I'd like to remind everyone that our lives are not on lock.
出于与尼根的互相尊重
Out of personal respect to the mutual nature with Negan,
但尼根现在失踪了
but Negan is M.I.A..
西蒙接管了  他已经要求产量指数级增加
Simon has taken over, and he has requested an exponential acceleration of production.
快速造更多子弹
More shots on the lickety-quick.
即使我们不顾生产安全
Even if we're double-timing it around the clock
日以继夜赶工
with nary a carey for workplace safety,
也会与不切实际的订单存在巨大差距
it isn't gonna prevent us from meeting our quixotic quota by the proverbial crap-ton.
我们唯可指望的是
The best that we can hope for
想办法先造出所需的最低数量
is that we somehow manage to squeeze out the bare minimum number of rounds necessary
免得西蒙发现产量不足而惩罚我们
to avoid the consequences of Simon finding out how short we are.
不
No. ‭
马上把口罩戴好
Put that mask back on now.
我们最不能承担的事就是
The last thing we can afford is for yours truly
让本人染上你因不当处理内脏
to contract whatever kind of nasty infected you
而染上的恶心病毒
with your improper gut handling.
我目前认为  要么是流感
My current theory is that it's either influenza
要么是空气传播的隐球菌
or cryptococcosis and therefore airborne.
如果是血液病  你早就死了
If it was of the blood variety, you would've already been dead.
但现实是你体内依然有可通过打喷嚏
But the fact remains you're packing pathogens
传染的病原体
that can sting with a sneeze,
所以你在进行药物治疗的同时
making it imperative that you maintain your P.P.E.
必须佩戴个人防护装备
at all times while your meds run their course.
现在张开手
Now hold out your hand.
感受一下
Feel that.
底火不平
Primers aren't flush.
这种成品子弹存在致命风险
The finished rounds pose the deadly risk
装入枪膛就可能走火
of slam-firing as soon as they're loaded into the chamber.
鉴于这种缺陷触手可知
Given that this imperfection is readily evident to the touch,
我只能猜测你是故意疏忽的
I can only assume that this oversight was purely intentional.
不是
No.
我不知道
I didn't know.
我只想要一个打不响的哑弹
I just wanted to make it so that the bullets didn't work.
并不想伤害任何人
I wasn't trying to hurt anyone.
我不希望自己人有任何牺牲
I don't want any of my people to die.
如果你不能接受我们现在才是你的自己人
If you cannot accept that we're your people now,
你完全可以省去麻烦
you may as well cut to the chase
亲自品尝生产线上的下颗子弹
and chew the next bullet coming off that line.
你希望这样吗
Is that what you want?
不
No.
我不希望这样
That's not what I want.
我不希望
I don't want that.
我不想帮你
I don't want to help you.
但是
But...
我也怕死
I do fear death.
也许这一切  是上帝用祂的方法
Maybe all this...maybe this is just his way
告诉我  我并没有改变
of showing me ‭that I haven't changed...
告诉我  我还是从前那个
a way of showing me that I'm still
把教民锁在外面的恶人
the same person who locked my parishioners out so long ago.
我还是那个吓破胆的禽兽
I'm still the same scared animal,
和你一样  做着能让自己苟且偷生的事
doing what I must to survive just like you.
也许不久之后
Being alive may be something
活着就不是我们的共同点了
we don't have in common for much longer.
你现在被停职了
You are hereby suspended from the line.
去找个不显眼的角落
Go find an unobtrusive corner
自己难受去  手套别摘了
and stow your load ‭and keep your mitts to yourself.
哭声别太大
And try not to cry too loud.
我想去外面测试一下
I want to go outside and test-fire some of these rounds
你还没有破坏的子弹
that you didn't compromise with your chicanery.
看到我很吃惊吗
Surprised to see me?
不应该的
Shouldn't be.
我当然吃惊了
Hell yeah, I'm surprised.
我们找到了你的车  西蒙以为...
We found your car, ‭and Simon thought that...
帮把手好吗
Give me a hand with this, will you?
说实话  当瑞克把我逼到
Not gonna lie...a real punch in the dick
满是腐尸的地下室
when Rick cornered me in the basement
而你们却没来的时候
with those decomposing assholes
真是令我难过
and you fellas never showed up.
西蒙想着...
Simon thought...
我想知道你的想法
I want to know what you were thinking.
我想知道你还记不记得自己是谁
See, I want to know if you remember who you are.
这次谈话不外传
This little talk ‭is just between me and you.
西蒙是你的二把手
Simon's your number two.
我以为你想让他做决定
I thought you wanted him calling it.
我记得我是谁
I remember who I am.
我是尼根
I'm Negan.
很好
Good.
我就想听到这个
That's what I like to hear.
帮我个忙
Now do me a favor.
把烟在这灭了
Put that smoke out right there.
等时机成熟
See, when the time comes --
你会知道何时成熟的
and you will know when it comes --
我希望你记住我们的谈话
I want you to remember this little talk.
我希望你记住我们以前的成就
I want you to remember what we've done
以及我们以后能取得的成就
and what we can still do together.
我以为他们杀了你  你死了  就像...
I thought they killed you and that you were gone, like --
就像那样
-- like that.
我缺乏纪律
I lacked discipline.
我带入了私人情绪
And I made it personal.
所以我才把对山顶寨的命令从感染
And that's why I moved things from infection to extermination
改成了消灭
at the Hilltop.
没错
Yes...
出了岔子
things went bad.
尽管我觉得不管用何种方法
Though I think it's possible we may have found ourselves
我们都可能陷入同样危险的境地
in a similar tactical situation, regardless of approach.
这很难说
We don't know that.
我认了
So I'll own it.
我只求你原谅我这一次
I just ask that you give me a pass on this one.
我会补偿你的
I'll make it up to you.
我保证
I promise you that.
我还记得当我占领这里的时候
You know, I remember when I took this place.
当你帮我占领这里的时候
When you helped me take this place.
我当时也不确定想不想带着你
Wasn't sure I wanted to keep you on board.
在我之前
I mean, before me,
在一切有秩序之前
before there was a system in place,
你很久以前做的那些事
what you did, killing all those men,
杀的那些成人和孩子
those boys in that settlement so long ago,
很多人会觉得你是失心疯
a lot of people would think that is some psychotic shit.
像是一个精神错乱  失控  崩溃的恶鬼
Like that is the work of a demented,
才能做出那种事
broken, goddamn ghoul.
你根本不想和这种人合作
Like that's not someone that you want to work with,
更别提在一起了
let alone stand next to.
所以我想着我得盯好你
So I figured I'd keep my eye on you.
我的确是这么做的
And I did.
直到此刻前  一切都好像没有问题
And everything seemed to work out right up until this point.
我需要你给我跪下
I'm gonna need you on your knees.
你不打算做点什么吗  还是说你认命了
You gonna make a move, or is that it?
没什么好做的
No move to make.
没错
No.
的确没有
There isn't.
我原谅你了
All is forgiven.
起来吧
Get your ass up.
我们没事了
We're good.
我不会让你失望的
I won't let you down.
不会的
Not you.
我非常感谢
I appreciate the hell out of that.
我们就从这里开始
This is where we start --
我们的第一个新补给站
the first of our new staging posts.
我们不用占领山顶寨
See, we do not have to take the Hilltop.
我们只需要确保那些农民跑不出来
We just have to make sure that the farmers can't leave.
我们保持机动  轻装上路
We stay nimble. We stay light.
只要有人敢探头  我们就打他们
We plink their asses every time one of them tries to poke their head out.
有时候从正前面  有时候从一英里之外
Sometimes right in front, sometimes from a mile away,
但每次都会打
but every goddamn time.
明天下午
Tomorrow afternoon,
我要率领一支十人小队去这里
I am going to take a 10-head team to this spot.
存下补给和机灵鬼博士做的弹药
I am stocking it with supplies and ammo that Dr. Smartypants are making.
这里的其他人要在不同的地点
Everyone else here is gonna do the same thing,
同时做同样的事
same time, different spot.
到明天晚上  我们就在山顶寨边
End of day tomorrow, we will have cache after cache
有了一圈据点
around that Hilltop
距离足够我们随时补给
and always be spitting distance from a reload.
安排小队全天候把守山顶寨
There will be teams 24/7 around that place...
狙杀他们  一个接一个  一天接一天
snipin' them, one by one, day after day,
直到我们
until we have full...
杀光他们
attrition.
我只能说  这是一项非常有雄心的计划
It's an ambitious plan with testicular heft, I'll give you that.
很高兴你回来了  老大
Very happy to have you back, boss man.
回来可真好
Damn good to be back.
好了  大家散会吧
All right, everybody, clear out.
除了你  德怀特
Except for you, Dwight.
我们还有些事要谈
Got a few things we need to kick around.
你很聪明
You are smart as hell.
你知道吗
You know that?
即使发生了这么多事
I mean, after everything --
雪莉  烫伤
Sherry, the sizzle...
你没有焦躁  你没做蠢事
you didn't stew, ‭you didn't do anything stupid.
你只是朝自己想要的迈进
You just went about the business of getting yours.
没什么能撼动你
Nothing shook you.
你一直紧盯着
You kept your eyes
能让你好好活下去的事物
on what could keep you alive and well.
你保持着头脑清醒
You keep on ‭keeping that shit clear.
我不禁怀疑
I can't help but suspect
我被活捉是因为
that the reason I'm being taken alive is, despite...
虽然我们之间有不容置疑的过节
what completely warranted bad blood exists between us,
但你们仍念及我们昔日的情分
you still harbor a vestigial nostalgia for our erstwhile camaraderie.
鉴于此  我愿意闭上本人的嘴
And in light of that, i'm willing to just shut my grub flap
给你们空间
and give you your space
直到你们准备好打破沉默
until you see such a time as you're ready to break the ice,
一个旅伴...
one traveling companion --
闭上狗嘴  否则我把你舌头割下来
Shut your mouth ‭before I cut your tongue out!
好了
All right!
我们得继续前进
We got to keep going.
他们肯定已经出来找他了
They have to be out looking for him by now.
-谢谢你  我...  -闭嘴
- Thank you. I -- - ‭Shut up.
走
Let's go. ‭
我告诉尼根我造了子弹
When I told Negan I made the bullet,
是为了救你
it was to save your life.
我当时没多想  就是帮你说话
I didn't think. ‭I just acted on your behalf.
我以为棍棒击下来的声音
And I fully expected the crack of the bat
会是我最后听到的声音
to be the last thing I heard,
但那并没发生
but that didn't happen.
然后我想着他们会折磨我
And then I thought they would torture me.
但他们没有
But they didn't.
他们给了我一个活下去的机会
They gave me a chance to live.
我试过抗拒
And I tried to resist.
我试着战胜自己的本性
I tried to rise above my biological imperative,
但我不是那样的人
but that is not who I am.
我知道你是什么样的人
I know who you are.
他们能逃离救世堂都是因为你
You're the reason they were able to escape the Sanctuary.
之后发生的所有事
Everything that's happened since then,
死的每个人  都怪你
everyone who's died, that's on you.
是瑞克迫使我们挑战救世军
Rick's the one who pushed us all to take the Saviors on.
是他不做好准备就一头扎进这趟浑水
He's the one who jumped headlong into this shit-storm with no waders.
你自私无比
You're selfish,
你还是个懦夫  叛徒
and you're a coward, and you're a traitor.
你背叛了你此生仅有的朋友们
You turned you back on the only friends you ever had.
在这里一枪打爆你的脑袋
Shooting you in the head right here
会让世界更美好
would actually make the world a better place.
但我们不打算杀你
But we're not gonna kill you,
不是因为我们在乎你
not because ‭we give a rat's ass about you.
我们只是需要你脑子里的知识
We just need what's in there!
我们会把你关进最阴暗的黑洞里
We're gonna stick you in the darkest hole we can find,
你唯一能看到阳光的机会
and the only time ‭you'll see the light of day
是我们需要你教我们做某事的时候
is when we need you ‭to teach us how to do something.
所以别担心  你会如愿的
So don't worry -- you'll get what you want.
你会活下去
You'll live.
但我们会逼你用你可悲的人生
But we're gonna force you to do something useful
做些有用的事
with your pathetic life.
明天下午  尼根和十个手下在X处
圆圈处各有一支十一人小队
杀死尼根  杀死剩下的人  了结这一切
会议进行得很顺利
Meeting went well.
已经恢复原状
Status quo has been re-achieved.
他为什么留下你
What'd he hold you back for?
就是给我打打气
You know, a... pep talk.
我们得谈谈
Mm. We need to talk.
跟其他对现任管理层有意见的人认真谈谈
A serious talk with the others who are less than thrilled with the current management,
他们像你一样  曾参与过
who, like you, engaged in activities
会令该管理层不满的活动
said management would frown on.
-真要这么做吗  -做不好就去死
- So this is it? - ‭You deliver or get shipped.
他没把事情做好  那让我难过
He hasn't delivered, and that saddens me.
但时候到了
But the time has come.
让我们集合志同道合的人
Let us gather ‭our like-minded individuals,
齐心协力
draw strength from each other...
做我们需要做的事
and do what we need to do.
不是吧
Come on.
我还得说服你吗
I gotta sell this to you?
想想他对你做过的事
Think about everything he's done to you,
他从你身上夺走的每一分尊严  你的一切
every little indignity, everything he's extracted from you.
好好想想  德怀特  你知道该怎么做
Think about it, Dwight! You know what you have to do.
巡逻完之后  来院子见我们
You have to meet us in the courtyard after rounds,
然后我们开始下一步
and we begin what's next.
天啊  好吗
I mean, Jesus, right?
好
Right.
很好  乖孩子
Yes, my boy.
很好
Yes.
它们一定是听见停车声了
They must've heard us pull up.
交给我
I got it.
看好他
Watch him.
该死
Shit.
他不可能跑远
He couldn't have got far.
来吧
Come on.
我们不能让他回去
We can't let him get back to them!
如果你看到他  打爆他的猪头
If you see him, blow that pig's head off!
天啊
Oh, God.
他死了吗
Is he dead?
你们
You...
把娜塔尼亚的死
You blamed Enid...
归咎在伊妮德头上
for Natania's death.
但其实这都是救世军的错
But it's really the Saviors.
他们对你们做的事  他们逼你们成为的人...
What they did to you, what they turned you into...
都是他们的错
it's their fault.
你们躲起来
You hide.
不相信别人
You don't trust.
因为他们  你们不过自己想过的生活
You don't live the life the way you want to because of them.
他们伤害过你们
They hurt you,
而且他们会继续伤害你们
and they're gonna keep on hurting you.
除非你们做一件事
Unless you do one thing!
反抗
Fight.
真扯
Some shit, huh?
是啊
Yeah.
我想着
Got to think, uh...
你一定比我们更想做这事
you wanted this before we did.
如果你来了这里  就证明你加入了
If you're here right now, you're in.
我们可以讨论方法和策略  但是你加入了
We can talk about approaches and finesses, but you are in.
不能反悔
No takebacks.
我们动手要快  安静  怀着敬意
We need to make this quick, quiet, and respectful.
他为我们做过很多事
Man's done a lot for us.
这是他应得的待遇
He deserves that.
你
You...
和他有私怨
have some legitimate personal issues with the man.
如果你想的话  你可以杀他
The kill is yours if you want it.
用安静的方法
Something quiet.
不是说用刀
I mean, not a knife.
不能那么恩怨用事
Can't make it that personal.
用消音器
A silencer.
我们召集会议
We call a meeting.
然后动手
And that's it.
接下来的任务是接好断骨
The next order of business is to set the break,
开始疗伤
to start the healing.
实现这一点的催化剂
The catalyzing event to facilitate that
就是消灭山顶寨和其居民
is the destruction of the Hilltop and its residents.
建成一座服从我们的纪念碑
We'll make it a monument of compliance.
抱歉  格雷戈里
Sorry, Gregory.
然后
And then...
我们继续生活
we get on with our lives.
对吧  德怀特
Right, Dwight?
谢了  小德
Thank you, D.
接下来换我
I'll take it from here.
三
Three...
二
two...
一
one.
德怀特
Dwight!
这才是我认识的西蒙
Now there is the Simon that I know.
他直来直去  而不是背后捅刀
He comes right at you instead of that backstabby bullshit.
为什么
Why?
他对你做了那么多事
After everything he did to you, huh?
为什么要这样做
Why do this?
他会赢的
He'd win.
你杀了垃圾场的人  西蒙
You killed ‭all the garbage people, Simon.
在我特别下令别那样做之后
After I specifically told you not to do that shit.
但是
But...
即使发生了这些事  即使我的为人你知道
after all this, and me being me...
我依然会给你一个机会
I'm still gonna give you your shot.
想当老大  必须先打败老大
You want to be the man, you got to beat the man.
如果你能做到
If you can do that...
那么  去他的
then, hell...
你来当老大
you should be the man.
各位
Everyone!
完事以后  继续工作
After this is done, we get to work.
你们要知道我并不想这样
Just know that I didn't want this.
但救世堂必须屹立下去
But the Sanctuary must stand.
这男人解决不了冲突
This is not the man to prosecute this conflict.
我只想说
Just wanted to say...
一小群人...
a grateful enclave --
...感谢你
unh! -- thanks you!
你得赶紧走
You need to get out of here now.
那还用说
No shit.
把这个给瑞克
Give this to Rick
告诉他明天的事
and tell him about tomorrow.
你只能这样做了
It's the only move you got.
我在输煤管后面给你留了一辆车
I left a car for you behind the coal chutes.
走吧
Go.
你在山顶寨全力出击
You went for it all at the Hilltop.
你害死了救世军的人
You got Saviors killed,
然后你像个懦夫一样逃跑了
and then you ran away like a coward!
你失败太多次了
You got shown up one too many times.
那些人总会觉得
Those people, they are always gonna know
有漏洞可钻  有办法逃避
that there's a loophole, a way to skate.
他们会一直找机会反抗
They are always gonna be looking for that chance to push back,
所以我现在必须杀光他们
so now I gotta kill all of 'em
就像我要杀掉你一样
just like I'm gonna kill you!
真是个混蛋
What an asshole.
我们该怎么办
What're we gonna do?
真他妈可惜  真浪费
Such a damn shame -- a waste --
像个没鸡巴的虫子一样在我背后偷摸搞事
slinking behind my back like some kind of dickless worm.
计划着杀了我
Planning on killing me...
我除了掐断他的脖子
Like, what else am I gonna do
还有什么选择呢
besides crush the guy's throat?
是啊
Yeah.
知道吗
Eh, you know,
西蒙的坏事  对你来说是好事
what's bad for Simon, it's good for you.
我知道我们关系时好时坏  小德
And I know we've had our ups and downs, D,
但我总是能依靠你
but I've always been able to count on you.
所以
So...
恭喜
congratulations.
你现在是我的新得力手下了
You are my new right-hand man.
当然前提是你接受晋升
That is, ‭if you accept the promotion.
我接受
I do.
我会帮你解决和瑞克的事
And I'll help you ‭finish this thing with Rick.
别小看自己  小德
Don't sell yourself short, D.
你已经帮我解决了
You already have.
你看起来很惊讶  德怀特
Well, you look surprised, Dwight.
我在路边找到了她
Yeah, see, I found her on the side of the road.
劳拉  告诉小德你对我说了什么
Laura, why don't you tell D what you told me?
在亚历山大的那一夜  他背叛了我们
That night in Alexandria, he turned on us.
他害死了我们小队
He killed our team.
我跑掉了  我一直在跑
I ran, and I kept on running.
我受伤了
I was hurt.
但支撑我活下来的动力是回到这里
But what kept me alive was the thought of getting back here
揭露你这个叛徒人渣
and exposing you ‭for the scum weasel you are.
现在一切都说得通了
It all makes sense now.
你告诉了瑞克该何时进攻
You told Rick when to attack.
怎么占领哨站
How to get to the outposts...
你把我们困在了这里
You keep us locked in here,
偷偷给他们工人的枪
slipping them workers guns.
也许你说杀了雪莉也是骗我的
Maybe you even lied to me about killing Sherry.
该死
Oh, hell.
那件事你肯定是骗我了
You, for sure, lied to me about that.
所以呢
So, what? Hmm?
你以为你是英雄吗
You think you're some sort of a hero?
不  你什么都不是
No. You are nothing.
一个糊涂的无名小卒
A nobody in way over your head.
但当我说
But when I said
每当我有需要  你从不令我失望时
that you would come through for me when I needed it,
我是110%认真的
oh, I meant that 110%.
我知道我能指望你把我的计划告诉瑞克
See, I knew ‭that I could count on you to deliver my plan to Rick,
我那聪明绝顶的假计划  要我说的话
my brilliant, if I do say so myself, fake-ass plan.
你让格雷戈里传话去了  对吧
You used Gregory for that, right?
我还以为
I mean, I was thinking
你会找借口外出什么的  但是
maybe you'd take some kind of field trip or something, but...
你给自己找了个送信小哥
no, you got yourself a little delivery boy.
好样的
Good for you.
把情报送给瑞克和小小巡逻队
To deliver all that intel to Rick and the piss patrol
会引他们直接走进枪林弹雨
that's gonna lead them directly into the line of fire.
他们根本反应不过来
They are not gonna know what hit 'em,
这都要感谢我的新得力手下
all thanks to my new right-hand man.
听着  我想过杀了你  但是
Now, see, I -- I thought about killing you, and then...
我想着这种死法对一个像你这样的
I thought maybe that'd be too dignified for a...
背后捅刀的两面派人渣来说太有尊严了
backstabbing, double-crossing dirtbag such as yourself.
不  小德
No, Dwighty boy,
我给你准备了计划
I got plans for you.
发生了什么
What the hell happened?
准备好守卫这里
We need preparations to defend this place
以防被再次入侵
in case of another incursion.
我们已经设好了警戒线
We've established a perimeter.
我们刚收到了救世堂的信息
We just got a message from the Sanctuary.
尼根回来了
Negan's back,
他计划灭掉山顶寨
and he has plans to finish the Hilltop.
瑞克会步入陷阱
Rick's walking into a trap.
我们明早需要完成子弹订单
We'll need that bullet order filled by tomorrow morning.
请转达尼根
Kindly convey to Negan
我个人对他回归的祝贺
my personal congratulations on the occasion of his return,
并向他保证他的要求
and assure him that his request
在数量和时间上都将得到满足
will be fulfilled ‭in its entirety and on time.
没错
That's right.
如果尼根需要子弹来结束这场战争
If Negan needs bullets to end this war,
那么毫无疑问  他会得到的
then, by ginger, he's gonna get 'em.
全都会得到
All of 'em.
忘记我所说的最低数量
Scotch my talk of a bare minimum.
不  女士们先生们
No, sirs and madams,
我们要在苦境中迎难而上
we shall rise to the occasion with the ammunition.
我们要用每发子弹震撼他们
We will blow them away with every trigger pull they require.
我们该这样  我们会这样
We shall, we will.
别搞错了  同事们
Oh, trip not, colleagues.
我们会永远改变救世军的历史
We will change Savior history evermore.
加百利
Gabriel.
所有人都得上
It's all hands on deck,
你来分拣弹壳
and yours are sorting shells.
听着  严格遵守我的命令
Listen, you follow my lead to the letter on the lead,
不然你就哭着去死吧
or you can cry and die.
开始
Here we go.
让我们用可悲的人生做些有用的事吧
Time to do something useful with our pathetic lives.
尼根  我是米琼恩
Negan, it's Michonne.
我会等着
I'll wait.
留脏辫  拿刀那个吗
The one with the dreads, the sword?
是你吗
Is that you?
瑞克在你身边吗
Rick there with you?
何不让他通话
Why don't you put him on?
我打给你不是为了瑞克  而是为了卡尔
This isn't about Rick. It's about Carl.
他给你写了一封信
He wrote you a letter.
我要给你  因为这是他的心愿
And I'm delivering it because that's what he wanted.
我可不保证不杀信使
Well, I can't promise not to kill the messenger.
闭嘴听好
Just shut up and listen.
尼根  我是卡尔
"Negan, this is Carl."
我在帮助某人时
"I was helping someone.
被咬了
I got bit.
我们都不用做我们在做的事
We didn't even have to be doing what we were doing.
我只是在帮某人
I was just helping someone.
现在我要死了
Now I'm gone.
你也许也死了
You might be gone.
也许我爸爸逼你的人交出了你  然后杀了你
Maybe my Dad made your people give you up and he killed you,
但我不这么觉得
but I don't think so.
我觉得你还活着  你在想出路
I think you're still around and you're working on a way out.
也许你想到了
Maybe you got out.
也许你觉得我们无药可救
Maybe you think we're a lost cause
只想杀光我们
and you just want to kill all of us.
我觉得你以为自己变成这样是被迫的
I think you think you have to be who you are.
我只想知道这是不是你想要的
I just wonder if this is what you wanted.
我想问你
I wanted to ask you.
我希望我能问你
I wish I could've.
也许你会打败我们
Maybe you'll beat us.
如果你打败了  以后也会有别的敌人
And if you do, there'll just be someone else to fight.
出路是一起合作
The way out is working together.
是原谅
It's forgiveness."
是相信没必要非得战斗
"It's believing that it doesn't have to be a fight anymore.
因为确实没必要
"Because it doesn't.
我希望我爸爸向你提出休战
"I hope my dad offers you peace.
我希望你接受
I hope you take it.
我希望一切都能改变
I hope everything can change.
对我来说改变了
It did for me.
你依然可以
Start over.
重新开始
You still can.
卡尔
Carl."
这一切
All this...
已没有出路
there is no getting out of it now.
即使你们跪着来求我
I wouldn't accept your surrender
我也不会接受投降
if you came to me on your knees.
胜利的关键不在于打败你们
See, winning isn't about beating you.
而在于杀光你们所有人
Winning is about killing every last one of you.
这才叫重新开始
That is starting over.
我从来不想这样
I never wanted this.
都是瑞克逼的
Rick made this happen.
你就这样转告他
You tell him that.
对话到此为止
No more talk.